Guide to the Stephen Prigozy telegraph collection, circa 1844-2016.
Prigozy, Stephen telegraph collection
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Stephen Prigozy telegraph collection, circa 1844-2016.
4739
Prigozy, Stephen,
20.4 cubic feet.
Telegraphs, photographs, correspondence, clippings, and telegraph equipment.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Photographs, correspondence, telegraph equipment and ephemera including a Western Union doll, telegrams, stock certificates, periodicals, pamphlets, sales catalogs, posters, stamps, clippings, and other items relating to the history of the telegraph, mainly in the United States. Also, photographs, clippings, and correspondence concerning the early history of the telephone.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Cornell University Class of 1952 (Bachelor of Electrical Engineering, 1953). Prigozy went on to become a professor of electrical engineering at the United States Merchant Marine Academy in Kings Point, New York.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Photographs, correspondence, telegraph equipment and ephemera including a Western Union doll, telegrams, stock certificates, periodicals, pamphlets, sales catalogs, posters, stamps, and other items relating to the history of the telegraph, mainly in the United States, beginning before the Civil War. The collection includes various publications and objects relating to Western Union in particular, as well as American Rapid Telegraph Company, Atlantic Telegraph Company, U.S. Telegraph Company, Wells Fargo, Nichols Electric Company, and the United States Army Signal Corps. Authors of other publications include R.W. Russell of American Telegraph Company; the Morse Telegraph Club; firms Green, Eckert, Sibley and Wade, Orton; and Stephen Prigozy himself, who published a number of articles on the telegraph. Also included are copies of items from the collections of Prigozy's fellow telegraphy collector George Jay Kramer; letters from Lewis B. Coe, the author of a book on the telegraph; and a television script concerning Cyrus Field, a promoter of the transatlantic cable.
Technical items in the collection include telegraph senders and receivers, insulators, Western Union code books, switchboard specifications from 1929, a U.S. Army Signal Corps relay, a Vibroplex relay, catalogs of telegraph equipment, and issues of Western Union's periodical, Technical review.
Also included in the collection are two volumes documenting the court case, Benjamin B. French et al. vs. Henry J. Rogers et al. (1850-1851), concerning a telegraph patent.
Collection also includes photographs, clippings, and correspondence concerning the early history of the telephone.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Prigozy, Stephen,; Coe, Lewis, 1911-; Field, Cyrus W. (Cyrus West), 1819-1892.; French, Benjamin B. (Benjamin Brown), 1800-1870.; Kramer, George J.; Rogers, Henry J., 1811-1879.; Russell, R. W.; American Rapid Telegraph Company.; Atlantic Telegraph Co.; Green, Eckert, Sibley (Firm); Morse Telegraph Club.; Nichols Electric Company.; U.S. Telegraph Company.; United States. Army. Signal Corps.; Wade, Orton (Firm); Wells, Fargo & Company.; Western Union Telegraph Company.
Subjects:
Telegraph -- United States -- History.; Telegraph -- Europe -- History.; Transatlantic cables.; Telephone -- History.
Form and Genre Terms:
Telegrams.; Stock certificates.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
NOTES
Books (approximately 21 additional cubic feet) are cataloged individually.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Historical
General Historical
S. Prigozy Research
Periodicals and Congressional Serials
Photographs and prints
Corporate History
Western Union
Other Companies
Series II. Technical
General
Periodicals and Journals
Series III. Telegrams
Pre-Civil War
Small Companies Alpha
Western Union
Foreign
General
Blanks
Stamps
Series IV. Consumer and Publicity
Series V. Machines and Memorabilia
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Historical
  - General Historical
    - Morse's Patent: Full Exposure of Dr. Charles T. Jackson's Pretensions to the Invention of the American Electro-Magnetic Telegraph (2 manuscripts), 1852, 1867 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      by Hon. Amos Kendall
    - Print of a portrait of Samuel Morse and a list of names that includes his signature, Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Map of the Submarine Telegraph between American and Europe, 1858 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - The Safety and Insulated Wire & Cable Co. Correspondence, 1898-1900 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Clipping & Chronologies, 1941, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      "Early History of the Telegraph" newspaper clipping, "Chronology of the Electric Spark", "Chronology of Telegraph Communications"
    - Centennial of the Telegraph, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Burlingame Telegraphing Typewriter, 1908-1912 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Emulation and Invention, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      by Brooke Hindle
    - Guide to Morse Exhibit by Karpeles Manuscript Library, May 26-27, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - 150th Anniversary of the First Electromagnetic Telegraph, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Historical Publications, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      "Jeptha H. Wade and the Cleveland and Cincinnati Telegraph Company" by Russel H. Anderson, "Marconi's History" by Gian Carlo Corazza, "From Connections to Collections" by Henry Petroski
    - The Extension of Submarine Telegraphy in a Quarter-Century, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 12)
      by Charles Bright
    - Binder: Copies of Collection of George Jay Kramer on Early Telegraph History, 1846-1870 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Copies from the Collection of George J. Kramer, 1848-1865 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Copies of articles about history of telegraph (1-2), n.d. (Box 1, Folder 15-16)
    - Material copied from internet about telegraph from c. late 1800s (1-2), n.d. (Box 1, Folder 17-18)
    - Copied materials on telegraph history (1-4), n.d. (Box 1, Folder 19-22)
    - Historical Research (1-5), n.d. (Box 9, Folder 1-5)
    - Stock and Bond Materials, 1883-1913 (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - List of Telegraph Offices and Calls of New York Central and Hudson River Railroad -- copy, August 1, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - "WGY Heard on an Indoor Aerial at Liverpool", December 28, 1922-January 3, 1923 (Box 18, Folder 12)
      Including correspondence with General Electric
    - Photograph of River Street -- copy, 1891 (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Guglielmo Marconi research, 1899, 1994-1995 (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - Postal Telegraph Cable Co. Poster, Reproduction of Map of Telegraph Lines, Enlargement of one section of 1853 map, Reproduction of Patent Design for Edison's Automatic Telegraph Perforator & Transmitter, 1853 (Mapcase-folder 1)
    - Map of the West India and Panama Telegraph Company, May 1874 (Mapcase-folder 1)
    - S. Prigozy Research
      - Concentrated Arc-Lamp, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 1)
      - Internet Telegraph Info, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 2)
      - Atlantic Cable, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 3)
      - Hawaiian Telegraph, 1903-1951 (Box 16, Folder 4)
      - Western Union, 1924-1932, 1994-1999 (Box 16, Folder 5)
      - Research on New Developments, 1949-1984 (Box 16, Folder 6)
        News clippings, advertisements, also includes outline for retirement party of J.W. Inwood
      - Essays on Radio History, ca. 1960s (Box 16, Folder 7)
      - Braille-Gram, 1975 (Box 16, Folder 8)
        Press releases, photographs, news clippings
      - Insulators, 1993, 2004 (Box 16, Folder 9)
      - Ezra Cornell/Cornell Library, 1995-1996 (Box 16, Folder 10)
      - Info on Telegrams and Covers, 1994-2006, 2012 (Box 16, Folder 11)
        Auction lists, photocopies
      - Telephone, 1994-1995 (Box 16, Folder 12)
      - Talk Given by S. Prigozy -- Telegraph Similitudes Used as Early Junk Mail, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 13)
      - Notes on Books, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 14)
      - Bibliographies, 1996-1999 (Box 16, Folder 15)
      - Correspondence with Robert Dalton Harris, 1993-2008 (Box 16, Folder 16)
        Harris is a dealer in telegraphica from West Sand Lake, NY and friend who worked with his wife Diane DeBlois at a business called AGatherin'
      - Correspondence with Lewis B. Coe, 1994-2001 (Box 16, Folder 17)
        Author of two books in the collection, one on telegraph and one of telephone
      - Correspondence with Bob Voss, 1998 (Box 16, Folder 18)
        "Another 'telegraph pal' -- Bob Voss visited us twice in Averill Park"
      - Stamp Catalog, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 19)
      - Sales Catalogs, 1977, 1997-1999 (Box 16, Folder 20)
      - Auction Catalog for Collection of George J. Kramer, September 15, 1990 (Box 16, Folder 21)
      - Auction Research, 1992-2005 (Box 16, Folder 22)
      - Philatelic Dealers, 1993, 2013 (Box 16, Folder 23)
      - Auction Lots, News Clippins and Articles, 1989, 1998-2006, 2014 (Box 16, Folder 24)
      - Price Lists, 2005-2013 (Box 16, Folder 25)
      - Misc. Small S. Prigozy Materials, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 26)
        Labels, "telegram" to S. Prigozy, Ghana envelope, Tress brochure
      - Auction Catalog "Western Electric Telephone Apparatus and Supplies", 2002; CD-2413 (Box 16, Folder 26)
      - Stephen Prigozy Membership to Morse Telegraph Club, 1997, 2012 (Box 16, Folder 27)
      - "Cyrus Field" TV Script, May 17, 1954 (Box 16, Folder 28)
        by Warner Law
      - Correspondence with David Hochfelder and Jeff Meador, 2008 (Box 16, Folder 43)
        Letters mention "Bob" who is Robert Dalton Harris.
      - Periodical Guide, 1852-1868 (Box 18, Folder 8)
        Dates refer to highlighted/listed issues of interest
  - Periodicals and Congressional Serials
    - 24th-33rd Congress House and Senate Documents, 1837-1854 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - 34th Congress House Documents, 1856 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - 35th Congress Senate and House Documents, 1858-1860 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - 36th-39th Congress House and Senate Documents, 1861-1866 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - 40th & 41st Congress House and Senate Reports, 1869-1871 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - US House Report Postal Telegraph in the United States, 1870 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - 43rd-45th Congress House and Senate Documents, 1875-1879 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - 42nd Congress House and Senate Documents, 1872-1874 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - 46th-48th Congress Senate and House Documents, 1881-1885 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Senate Report on the Postal Telegraph, 1884 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - 49th Congress House and Senate Documents (1), 1886 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - 49th Congress House and Senate Documents (2), 1885, 1887 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - 50th Congress House and Senate Documents, 1888 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - 51st-54th Congress House and Senate Documents, 1890-1896 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - 55th Congress House and Senate Documents, 1897 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - 56th Congress House and Senate Documents, 1900-1901 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - 57th and 58th House and Senate Documents, 1902-1904 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Report of the Superintendent of the Census, 1852 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Speech by S.R. Peters on the Telegraph Monopoly, 1888 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Hearings on the Subtext of Government Ownership and Control of the Telegraph Lines, 1894 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Supreme Court of Pennsylvania: Pennsylvania vs. The Western Union Telegraph Co., 1881 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Report on the Survey of Laying Cable between the U.S. and Hawaii, 1892 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - A Guide to Documents in the Congressional Series Relating to the Telegraph (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - A Review of an Argument in Support of the Limited Post and Telegraph, 1891 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Rates of Pay for Communication by Telegraph, 1904 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Post Master General Report, 1845 (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Government Ownership of the Telegraph and Telephone, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - The Great Telegraph Suit of Samuel F.B. Morse and Alfred Vail vs. Francis O.J. Smith, 1858 (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - New York Senate Memorial and an Act of the Maine Legislature, 1861, 1876 (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Issue of New York Weekly Tribune, 1843 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Issue of Boston Recorder and Telegraph, 1827 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Issues of The Illustrated London News, 1856-1859, 1866-1867 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Issues of Harper's Weekly, 1865-1872 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Issue of New York Observer, 1838 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Issue of New York Daily Tribune, 1843 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Issues of Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newsletter, 1879-1886 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Issue of New-Orleans Commercial Bulletin, January 10, 1870 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Issue of The World Morning Courier and New York Enquirer, October 26, 1861 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Issue of National Intelligencer, July 17, 1849 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Photographs and prints
    - Historical Photos and Illustrations, 1844-1890, 1924-1929, 1937 (Box 16, Folder 29)
    - Color print of a section of the Atlantic Cable, Carried by Adams & Cos Express Wagon in the Procession of the 1st September, Undated (Box 16, Folder 44)
    - Framed Photo: Section of the Atlantic Cable, Carried by Adams & Cos Express Wagon in the Procession of the 1st September, n.d. (Box 31)
    - Post Cards, 1906, 1910, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 30)
      2 photos featuring WU employees, 1906 features ruins of workshop where Morse invented the telegraph
    - Western Union: Los Angeles (1), c. 1939, 1952-1977 (Box 16, Folder 31)
      People, Sales Meetings
    - Western Union: Los Angeles (2), c. 1940, 1960, 1962, 1977 (Box 16, Folder 32)
    - Western Union Photographs (1), c. 1928-1941, 1958, 1970 (Box 16, Folder 33)
    - Western Union Photographs (2), c. 1939-1940, 1953, 1959 (Box 16, Folder 34)
    - Western Union Photographs (3), c. 1932, 1945, 1956-1959 (Box 16, Folder 35)
    - Western Union Photographs (4), c. 1945, 1949, 1960 (Box 16, Folder 36)
    - Hollywood-Related Photos, c. 1940, 1955 (Box 16, Folder 37)
    - Small Photographs, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 38)
      Some labeled "Inglewood, Calif."
    - Misc. Photographs, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 39)
      Kodak Envelope of Photos and Negatives, Photographs of Railroads, WU Photographs, Otto Rothschild Negative
    - Photograph of Man in Telegraph Office, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 40)
    - Photograph of Three Men in Front of a Telegraph Office, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 41)
    - Photograph of Telegraph Office, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 42)
    - Stereo views of the Western Union Telegraph Building and the Ship News Office in New York City, n.d. (Box 19)
  - Corporate History
    - Western Union
      - American Telegraphy After 100 Years, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 7)
        The Western Union Telegraph Company
      - Western Union Telegraph Company, 1901 (Box 1, Folder 23)
        Historical publication by WU (copy)
      - Telegraph Companies Forming Western Union, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 24)
        From diagrammatic charts prepared by the Western Union Telegraph Company showing its important constituents as existing on Dec. 31, 1914
      - WU memos, ca. 1920s (Box 1, Folder 25)
      - WU Annual Reports, 1924, 1946-1978 (Box 1, Folder 26)
      - WU Los Angeles Office (1), 1938-1973 (Box 1, Folder 27)
        Correspondence, press releases, photos, publications. Many materials involve Paramount Pictures.
      - WU Los Angeles Office (2), 1939-1969 (Box 1, Folder 28)
        Correspondence, press releases, photos, script entitled "Field and the Atlantic Cable". Many materials involve Paramount Pictures.
      - Payments and Bonds, 1871-1874, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 6)
        Western Union, Gold & Stock Telegraph Co., bond for Emanuel R. Posnack and Ann B. Posnack to Century Federal Savings and Loan Association
    - Other Companies
      - Various articles regarding investments and competition between companies, 1881-1930 (Box 1, Folder 29)
      - Remarks of R.W. Russell of American Telegraph Co. (copy), 1860 (Box 1, Folder 30)
      - Correspondence re: Postal Telegraph, 1875-1880 (Box 1, Folder 31)
      - American Rapid Telegraph Co., Atlantic Telegraph Co., Baltimore and Ohio Telegraph Co., 1882-1925 (Box 1, Folder 32)
      - American Telegraphone Company, 1900-1943 (Box 1, Folder 33)
      - Bartica Company, 1911, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 34)
      - Oxford Linen Mills, 1908-1914 (Box 1, Folder 35)
      - Sterling Debenture Corp. & other fraudulent Co.'s, 1910-1912 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - The Telepost Company, 1896-1917 (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - Booklet on Telepost History, Government Documents on The Telepost, Patents and Biographies of Patrick Delany, 1908-1925 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      - Copied Material on Telegraph Companies, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - Stocks, Bonds, Shares, 1868-1906 (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - Portfolio: Telegraph Stock Certificates, 1851-1935, 1955-1959, 1970 (Box 17)
      - Portfolio: Telegraph Stock Certificates, 1889, 1907-1918, 1930 (Box 17)
        Largely Telepost and Bartica Co.
      - Portfolio: Telegraph Stock Certificates, 1888-1904, 1929-1971, 1981 (Box 17)
      - Map of West India and Panama Telegraph Co., 1874 (Box 18, Folder 5)
- Series II. Technical
  - General
    - Description of the American Electro Magnetic Telegraph, 1845 (Box 2, Folder 7)
      by Alfred Vail
    - US Patent Office: "Improvement in Magnetic Printing-Telegraphs", April 18, 1846 (Box 2, Folder 8)
      Patent no. 4,464; Royal E. House
    - Shaffner's Telegraphy Companion Devoted to the Science and Art of the Morse American Telegraph, January 1855 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Railroad and Telegraph Rates, 1866, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Velocity of the Electric Current over Telegraph Wire, June 1869 (Box 2, Folder 11)
      by G. W. Hough, A. M.
    - J.H. Bunnell & Co. Telegraphy Manual, 1883-1900 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - "Recent Contributions to Electric Wave Telegraphy", 1907 (Box 2, Folder 13)
      by Prof. J. A. Fleming
    - Telegraphy Guides, ca. 1910s, 1930s (Box 2, Folder 14)
      Instructional booklets on telegraphy engineering and operation by various companies
    - Misc. reports and booklets from WU, early 1900s (Box 2, Folder 15)
      Delicate
    - The World's Work: Pirates of Promotion, 1919 (Box 2, Folder 16)
      by Tal. P. Shaffner, Esq.
    - WU Office Documents, Employee Publications & Correspondence, 1921- 1927, 1951-1981 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Specifications for the Installation of Double Conductor Cordless Cabinet Type Switchboards, June 26, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Misc. Publications, 1949, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 19)
      "Power Supply for Low Power Radio Installation on Cabooses", "The Application of Facsimile to Commercial Radio Communications"
    - WU TELEX/TWX Guides, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Catalog of Telegraph Keys of US Army Signal Corps, 1993-1997 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Correspondence re: Canadian Telegraphs, 2003-2004 (Box 2, Folder 22)
      Regarding primarily mid. 1800s
    - Various Telegraph Books & Reports (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - WU code books, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Desk-Fax, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 25)
      Includes newspaper clipping and press release
    - Grove Cell/Carbon Battery Drawing, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - "The Story of the Greetings Telegraph Service in Great Britain", n.d. (Box 2, Folder 27)
      by John C. W. Field, F.R.G.S.
    - Binder: Machines & Batteries, etc.; Telephones; Incandescent Lamps (1), 1886-1935, 1956-1958 (Box 3)
      Most pages labelled "Electrical Machines"
    - Binder: Machines & Batteries, etc.; Telephones; Incandescent Lamps (2), 1886-1938, 1965 (Box 3)
      Batteries, Lightning Rods
    - Binder: Machines & Batteries, etc.; Telephones; Incandescent Lamps (3), 1886-1918, 1929-1944 (Box 3)
      Incandescent Lamps
    - Binder: Machines & Batteries, etc.; Telephones; Incandescent Lamps (4), 1878-1943 (Box 3)
      Telephones
    - Binder: Telegraph Equipment, Telegraph Schools & other items, 1848-1930 (Box 4)
    - Binder: Cable Rates and Corporate Correspondence, 1921-1937 (Box 4)
      WU, Postal Telegraph, RCA Communications, C. Bensinger Co., French Telegraph Cable Company, correspondence with various companies regarding telegraph services
  - Periodicals and Journals
    - Telegraph & Telephone Stamp Society and Journal of the Telegraph Study Circle: Bulletin and Across the Wire Issues, 1987-1990 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Harper's New Monthly Magazine: "The Telegraph", n.d. (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Scribner's Monthly: "Telegraphing in Battle", May 1886 (Box 2, Folder 30)
      by J. Emmett O'Brien
    - McClure's Magazine: "Marconi's Wireless Telegraph", June 1899 (Box 2, Folder 31)
      by Cleveland Moffett
    - Issues of Journal Telegraph, 1910-1912 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - "Beiblätter zu den Annalen der Physik", 1912 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Proceedings of the American Institute of Electrical Engineers, March 1906, May 1911 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Proceedings of the Institute of Radio Engineers, February 1924 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Antique Wireless Association: The Federal Telegraph Company 1909-1920, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Telegraph World, May 1930 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - WU Publications, 1939-1967 (Box 3, Folder 3)
      Telegraph News, Telegraph World, The Monitor
    - Scientific American Articles, July 1962, August 1975 (Box 3, Folder 4)
      "Telephone Switching" (July 1962), "How there came to be only one telephone company in town" (August 1975)
    - Postal History Journal, June 2012 (Box 3, Folder 5)
      Includes article by Stephen Prigozy
    - WU Technical Review, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - WU Technical Reviews, 1949-1951 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - WU Technical Reviews, 1951-1954 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - WU Technical Reviews, 1955-1957 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - WU Technical Reviews, 1958-1961 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Issues of "The Operator", 1874-1876, 1883 (Box 17)
    - Issues of Scientific American, 1877, 1884, 1893-1896, 1902-1903, 1909 (Box 18, Folder 1)
      Includes 50th Anniversary issue
    - Issues of Journal of the Telegraph, 1868 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Issues of Electric Age, January 1891 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - "The Federal Telegraph Company", 1979 (Box 20, Folder 12)
      by Thorn L. Mayes
    - Proceedings of the IEEE, September 1976 (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - Tele, 1953 (Box 20, Folder 14)
      English edition, No. 1
    - Dots and Dashes, 2016 (Box 20, Folder 15)
- Series II. Telegrams
  - Pre-Civil War
    - Pre-Civil War Binder: New York Hinterland Lines, 1848-1864 (Box 5)
    - Pre-Civil War Binder: Old West Lines, 1847-1866, 1882 (Box 5)
    - Pre-Civil War Binder: American Telegraph Co. & U.S. Telegraph Co., 1856-1866, 1916 (Box 5)
    - Pre-Civil War Binder: New Orleans Hinterland Lines & New West Lines, 1848-1868 (Box 5)
    - Pre-Civil War Binder: New York to Boston Lines, 1847-1862 (Box 5)
    - Pre-Civil War Binder: Mid Atlantic Hinterland Lines & Boston Hinterland Lines, 1847-1919 (Box 6)
    - Pre-Civil War Binder: Washington to New York Lines, Boston to Canada Lines, Washington to New Orleans Lines, 1847-1862, 1888 (Box 6)
  - Small Companies Alpha
    - Binder: Telegrams from small companies, A & B, 1856-1891 (Box 6)
    - Binder: Telegrams from small companies, C to L, 1862-1906, 1923-1948 (Box 6)
    - Binder: Telegrams from small companies, M to Ne, 1855-1907, 1917, 1937-1938 (Box 7)
    - Binder: Telegrams from small companies, New to O, 1868-1911, 1936 (Box 7)
    - Binder: Telegrams from small companies, P to R, 1855-1875, 1888-1915 (Box 7)
    - Binder: Telegrams from small companies, S to Z, 1852-1905, 1925 (Box 7)
  - Western Union
    - Binder: WU Telegrams & Envelopes -- Green, 1878-1898 (Box 8)
    - Binder: WU Telegrams & Envelopes -- Eckert, 1893-1904 (Box 8)
    - Binder: WU Telegrams & Envelopes -- Sibley & Wade, 1851-1869 (Box 8)
    - Binder: WU Telegrams & Envelopes -- Orton, 1867-1879, 1914 (Box 8)
    - Binder: WU Telegrams & Envelopes -- Clowry & Vail, 1903-1922 (Box 9)
    - Binder: WU Telegrams & Envelopes -- Carlton, 1916-1941 (Box 9)